{
    "response_code":0,
    "results":
    [
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"QUIZ3","difficulty":"EXAM2","question":"Consider the following IPv6 address: 2001:0BEF:0BAD:0006::32/64. Which of these is correct?","correct_answer":"Prefix Length = /64","incorrect_answers":["Global Routing Prefix = ::32","Subnet ID = 2001:0BEF:0BAD","Interface ID = 2001:0BEF:0BAD:0006"],"explanation":"The IPv6 address 2001:0BEF:0BAD:0006::32/64 is a global unicast address. As such, it is composed of the following component parts: <ul><li>Global Routing Prefix: 2001:0BEF:0BAD</li><li>Subnet ID: 2001:0BEF:0BAD:0006</li><li>Interface ID: ::32</li></ul>Prefix Length: /64 <br><br>The Global ID is an element of unique local unicast addresses and is not associated with global unicast addresses.","section":"4.1","qnum":"01"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Consider the following IPv6 address: FD01:0001:0001:005::7/64    Which of these is correct?","correct_answer":"Global ID = 01:0001:0001","incorrect_answers":["Interface ID = ::7","Subnet ID = 01:0001:0001","Global Routing Prefix = FD01:0001:0001:005"],"explanation":"The IPv6 address FD01:0001:0001:005::7/64 is a unique local unicast address. As such, it is composed of the following component parts: <ul><li>Unique Local Unicast Prefix: FD</li><li>Global ID: 01:0001:0001</li><li>Subnet ID: FD01:0001:0001:005</li><li>Interface ID: ::7</li><li>Prefix Length: /64</li></ul><br><br>The Global Routing Prefix is a component of global unicast addresses and is not associated with unique local unicast addresses.","section":"4.1","qnum":"02"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"QUIZ3","difficulty":"EXAM2","question":"You need to design an IPv6 addressing scheme for your network. The following are key requirements for your design: <ul><li>Infrastructure hosts, such as routers and servers, will be assigned static interface IDs while workstations, notebooks, tablets, and phones will be assigned interface IDs dynamically.</li><li>    Internet access must be available to all hosts through an ISP.</li><li>  Site-to-site WAN connections will be created using leased lines.</li></ul> <br> Which type of IPv6 addressing is most appropriate for hosts in this network?","correct_answer":"Global Unicast Addressing","incorrect_answers":["Unique Local Unicast Addressing, Global Unicast Addressing","Unique Local Unicast Addressing, Global Unicast Addressing, Anycast Addressing","Link-Local Addressing"],"explanation":"Global unicast addressing should be used in this scenario because Internet access is required by network hosts. Global unicast addressing uses registered addresses and is equivalent to public addressing in IPv4. Because the addresses are registered with IANA, no other organization can use them on any public network, including the Internet. <br><br> Unique local unicast addresses are private addresses used for communication within a site or between a limited number of sites. These addresses are not registered with IANA and cannot be used on a public network without address translation. <br><br> Link-local addresses are assigned to all IPv6 interfaces on the network by default, but they can only be used on the local subnet. Routers never forward packets destined for local link addresses to other subnets. Anycast addresses are used to locate the nearest server of a specific type, for example the nearest DNS or network time server.","section":"4.1","qnum":"03"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"QUIZ3","difficulty":"EXAM2","question":"Which of the following is NOT a correctly-formatted IPv6 address?","correct_answer":"FE80:9978::AGA0:98B5","incorrect_answers":["2001::78:ABC:891F","::DAFC:8904","FE80::AB01:7894   ::DAFC:8904"],"explanation":"<ul><li>IPv6 addresses are made up of 32 hexadecimal numbers, organized into 8 quartets. 2001:0007:89FA:78C0:34AB:FFAC:775B:34CA:AAA1 is invalid because it has 9 quartets.</li><li>Each quartet is separated by a colon.</li><li>Each quartet is represented as a hexadecimal number between 0 and FFFF.</li><li>FE80:9978::AGA0:98B5 is invalid because it includes the letter G in one of the quartets.</li><li>Leading 0's within a quartet can be omitted. In the example above, 78 is the same as 0078, and ABC is the same as 0ABC.</li><li>Addresses with consecutive zeros can be expressed more concisely by substituting a double-colon for the group of zeros. However, only one set of consecutive 0's can be omitted.</li><li>FF00::A894::765F is invalid because it has two sets of omitted 0's. ::DAFC:8904 is valid because only one set has been omitted.</li></ul>","section":"4.1","qnum":"04"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Consider the following IPv6 address: FE80:0000:0000:0055:0000:0000:000A:AB00<br>Which of the following is a valid shortened form of this address?","correct_answer":"FE80::55:0000:0000:A:AB00","incorrect_answers":["FE80::55::A:AB00","FE80::55::A:AB","FE80::0055::000A:AB"],"explanation":"Valid shortened forms are: <ul><li>FE80::55:0000:0000:A:AB00</li><li>FE80:0000:0000:0055::000A:AB00 (FE80:0000:0000:55::A:AB00 could also be used)</li></ul><br>Leading 0s within a quartet can be omitted. For example, 0055 can be shortened as 55. Addresses with consecutive zeros can be expressed more concisely by substituting a double-colon for the group of zeros. However, only one set of consecutive 0s can be omitted.","section":"4.1","qnum":"05"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Which of the following IPv6 addresses is equivalent to the IPv4 loopback address of 127.0.0.1?","correct_answer":"::1","incorrect_answers":["::","FF02::1","FE80::1"],"explanation":"The IPv6 loopback address is ::1. The local loopback address is not assigned to an interface. It can be used to verify that the TCP/IP protocol stack has been properly installed on the host.<br>:: is the unspecified address (also identified ::/128). The unspecified address is used when there is no IPv6 address. It is typically used during system startup when the host has not yet configured its address. The unspecified address should not be assigned to an interface.<br>Multicast addresses have a FF00::/8 prefix. FF02::/8 is the multicast prefix for all nodes on the local link.","section":"4.1","qnum":"06"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"These IPv6 prefixes match with their descriptions: Link-local = FC00::/7, Multicast = FF00::/8, Unique local = 2000::/3","correct_answer":"False","incorrect_answers":["True","&nbsp;","&nbsp;"],"explanation":"<ul><li>FE80::/10 is the link-local prefix.</li><li>FF00::/8 is the multicast prefix..</li><li>FC00::/7 is the unique local prefix..</li><li>2000::/3 is an outdated prefix for global unicast addresses. In the future, global unicast addresses do not need to follow this standard.</li><li>2001:0DB8::/32 is a prefix reserved for documentation purposes. This prefix is guaranteed not to be used as a global unique address..</li></ul>","section":"4.1","qnum":"07"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Which of the following IPv6 addresses is used by a host to contact a DHCP server?","correct_answer":"FF02::1:2","incorrect_answers":["FE80::1:2","FE80::2","FF02::1"],"explanation":"FF02::1:2 is the IPv6 address used to contact a DHCP server. All addresses with the FF00::/8 prefix are multicast addresses. IPv6 uses multicasts instead of broadcasts. FF02::2 is the multicast address for all routers on the local link; FF02::1 is for all hosts on the link. FE80::/10 is the prefix for link-local unicast addresses.","section":"4.1","qnum":"08"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Which of these IPv6 addresses is matched to the correct address type?","correct_answer":"Link-local = FEA0::AB89:9FF:FE77:1234","incorrect_answers":["Broadcast = FF02::1:2","Multicast = FD00::8907:FF:FE76:ABC","Unique local = 2001:6789:9078::ABCE:AFFF:FE98:0001"],"explanation":"<ul><li>Unique local = 2001:6789:9078::ABCE:AFFF:FE98:0001</li><li>Based on previous standards, global unicast addresses start with 20, but can now include any prefix that is not reserved.</li><li>Addresses beginning with FC or FD are unique local addresses.</li><li>Addresses beginning with FE8, FE9, FEA, or FEB are link-local addresses.</li><li>Addresses beginning with FF are multicast addresses.</li></ul><br>There are no broadcast addresses in IPv6.","section":"4.1","qnum":"09"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Which IPv6 address type is only valid within a subnet?","correct_answer":"link-local","incorrect_answers":["unique local","multicast","global-multicast"],"explanation":"Link-local addresses (also known as local link addresses) are addresses that are valid on only the current subnet.<br>Unique local addresses are private addresses used for communication within a site or between a limited number of sites. Earlier IPv6 specifications defined a site-local address. The site-local address has been replaced with the unique local address. Global unicast addresses are addresses that are assigned to individual interfaces that are globally unique (unique throughout the entire Internet). Multicast addresses represent a dynamic group of hosts.","section":"4.1","qnum":"10"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Your organization has been assigned a registered global routing prefix of 2001:FEED:BEEF::/48 by an ISP. Using your organization's IPv6 addressing scheme, you've used the next 16 bits beyond the global routing prefix to define the following subnets: <ul><li>2001:FEED:BEEF:0001::/64 </li><li>2001:FEED:BEEF:0002::/64 </li><li>2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::/64 </li><li>2001:FEED:BEEF:0004::/64 </li></ul><br>You need to statically assign an interface ID of 0000:0000:0000:0001 to the router interface connected to the 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::/64 subnet.<br>Which interface configuration command would you use to do this?","correct_answer":"ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::1/64","incorrect_answers":["ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::/64 eui-64","ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::1/48","ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::/64"],"explanation":"The ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::1/64 command statically assigns an interface ID of 0000:0000:0000:0001 to the router interface connected to the 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::/64 subnet.<br>The ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::/64 command omits the interface ID to be assigned to the interface. <br>The ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::/64 eui-64 command statically assigns an interface ID to the router interface using its MAC address to construct the interface ID. <br>The ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0003::1/48 command specifies the wrong subnet for the scenario. <br>The ipv6 address 2001:FEED:BEEF:0002::1/64 command also specifies the wrong subnet for the scenario.","section":"4.2","qnum":"01"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Your organization has decided to implement unique local unicast IPv6 addressing. A global ID of FD01:A001:0001::/48 been selected for the organization's IPv6 addressing scheme. The next 16 bits beyond the global ID have been used to define the following subnets: <ul><li>FD01:A001:0001:0001::/64 </li><li>FD01:A001:0001:0002::/64 </li><li>FD01:A001:0001:0003::/64 </li><li>FD01:A001:0001:0004::/64 </li></ul><br>You need to statically assign an interface ID to a router interface connected to the FD01:A001:0001:0003::/64 subnet. To ensure uniqueness, the interface ID should be constructed using the MAC address of the router interface.<br>Which interface configuration command would you use to do this?","correct_answer":"ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0003::/64 eui-64","incorrect_answers":["ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0003::/48 eui-64","ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0003::1/64","ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0002::1/64"],"explanation":"The ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0003::/64 eui-64 command statically assigns an interface ID to a router interface connected to the FD01:A001:0001:0003::/64 subnet using the MAC address of the router interface. When you use the eu-64 option with the ipv6 address command, only the 64-bit network prefix for the address needs to be specified. The last 64 bits are automatically computed from the interface's MAC address.<br>The ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0003::1/64 command statically assigns an interface ID of 0000:0000:0000:0001 to the router interface. This is a valid interface ID for the subnet, but it does not use the MAC address of the router interface. The ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0002::1/64, ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0002::/64 eui-64, and ipv6 address FD01:A001:0001:0003::/48 eui-64 commands specify the wrong subnet for the scenario.","section":"4.2","qnum":"02"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Your company has just started contracting with the government. As part of the contract, you have configured a special server for running a custom application. Contract terms dictate that this server use only IPv6.<br>You have several hosts that need to communicate with this server. Hosts run only IPv4 and cannot be configured to run IPv6..<br>Which solution would you use to allow the IPv4 clients to communicate with the IPv6 server?","correct_answer":"NAT-PT","incorrect_answers":["Teredo","Dual stack","ISATAP"],"explanation":"The only solution that allows IPv4 hosts to communicate with the IPv6 server without running IPv6 on the client systems is Network Address Translation-Protocol Translation (NAT-PT). NAT-PT converts the IPv6 packet header into an IPv4 packet header, and vice versa. A translation table is referenced by the device as it converts the headers to ensure the packet is sent to the correct host.<br>A dual stack client is a host that runs both IPv4 and IPv6. In this scenario, it is not possible to run IPv4 on the server, and it is not possible to run IPv6 on the clients so a dual stack configuration is not possible.<br>Teredo, 6-to-4, and Intra-site Automatic Tunnel Addressing Protocol (ISATAP) are all tunneling protocols that allow an IPv6 host to communicate with another IPv6 host through an IPv4 network. None of the tunneling protocols enable an IPv4 host to communicate with an IPv6 host.","section":"4.2","qnum":"03"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Your company wants to begin the transition from IPv4 to IPv6. You want to stage the implementation on a host-by-host basis. You will enable IPv6 on existing hosts as time and budget allows. During the transition, all hosts in your site need to communicate with all other hosts. IPv6 should be used between hosts when both hosts support IPv6. NAT support is not required.<br>Which method should you use?","correct_answer":"ISATAP","incorrect_answers":["Manual tunnels","6-to-4","Teredo"],"explanation":"Use Intra-site Automatic Tunnel Addressing Protocol (ISATAP) to begin a transition to IPv6 within a site. You will need to install an ISATAP router and make each IPv6 host an ISATAP client. Both the router and the clients are dual-stack hosts, running both IPv4 and IPv6.<br>To allow hosts to communicate with both IPv4 and IPv6 hosts, you will need some form of dual stack configuration on the host computers. 6-to-4 and Teredo tunneling are for connecting IPv6 sites to other IPv6 sites through an IPv4 network. Manual tunneling requires establishing a tunnel association directly between two devices. On a network in transition, this would involve too much effort.","section":"4.2","qnum":"04"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"QUIZ3","difficulty":"EXAM2","question":"Which of the following are characteristics of 6-to-4 tunneling?","correct_answer":"Works through NAT, Tunnel endpoints configured on routers, Dual stack routers","incorrect_answers":["IPv4-only hosts communicate with IPv6-only hosts, Dual stack routers, Dual stack hosts","IPv4-only hosts communicate with IPv6-only hosts, Dual stack routers, Dual stack hosts, Manually-configured tunnel endpoints, Dual stack routers, Dual stack hosts","IPv4-only hosts communicate with IPv6-only hosts, Dual stack routers, Dual stack hosts Manually-configured tunnel endpoints, Dual stack routers, Dual stack hosts Dual stack hosts, Dual stack routers, Tunnel endpoints configured on routers"],"explanation":"6-to-4 tunneling has the following characteristics:<ul><li>Tunnel endpoints are configured on routers.</li><li>Routers are dual stack routers to allow the routers to tunnel IPv6 packets over the IPv4 network.</li><li>Works through NAT.</li><li>Tunnel endpoints are automatically configured, and IPv6 addresses are automatically assigned.</li><li>Host computers run IPv6 only.</li></ul><br>The only solution that allows IPv4-only hosts to communicate with IPv6-only hosts is Network Address Translation-Protocol Translation (NAT-PT).","section":"4.2","qnum":"05"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Which of the following are characteristics of Teredo tunneling?","correct_answer":"Tunnel endpoints configured on hosts, Works through NAT, Dual stack hosts","incorrect_answers":["IPv4-only hosts communicate with IPv6-only hosts, Dual stack hosts, Dual stack hosts","Dual stack routers, Dual stack hosts, IPv4-only hosts communicate with IPv6-only hosts","Dual stack routers, Dual stack hosts, IPv4-only hosts communicate with IPv6-only hosts, Dual stack hosts, IPv4-only hosts communicate with IPv6-only hosts,, Works through NAT"],"explanation":"Teredo tunneling has the following characteristics: <ul><li>Tunnel endpoints are configured on hosts.</li><li>Hosts are dual stack hosts and perform tunneling of IPv6 to send on the IPv4 network.</li><li>Works through NAT.</li></ul><br>The only solution that allows IPv4-only hosts to communicate with IPv6-only hosts is Network Address Translation-Protocol Translation (NAT-PT).","section":"4.2","qnum":"06"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"multiple","difficulty":"easy","question":"Which of the following are characteristics of ISATAP for IPv6 tunneling?","correct_answer":"Dual stack hosts and Dual stack routers","incorrect_answers":["Tunnel endpoints configured between routers","Works through NAT","Tunnel endpoints configured between hosts"],"explanation":"Intra-site Automatic Tunnel Addressing Protocol (ISATAP) is a tunneling method for use within a site to provide IPv6 communication over a private IPv4 network. With ISATAP, a dual stack ISATAP router creates a tunnel with a dual stack host. Tunneling is used to communicate over the IPv4 network. Because it is intended for use within a site, ISATAP does not work through NAT.","section":"4.2","qnum":"08"},
        {"category":"CHAPTER4","type":"QUIZ3","difficulty":"EXAM2","question":"You are working on a workstation with the following MAC address: 10-01-64-AB-78-96<br>Which of the following will be the link-local address using the modified EUI-64 format?","correct_answer":"FE80::1201:64FF:FEAB:7896","incorrect_answers":["FC00::1001:64FF:FEAB:7896","FE80::1001:64AB:7896:FFFF","FC00::1001:64AB:7896"],"explanation":"Link-local addresses have a prefix of FE80::/10, meaning that they begin with FE80, FE90, FEA0, or FEB0. On Ethernet networks, the modified EUI-64 format interface ID can be automatically derived from the MAC address using the following process: <ul><li>1-The MAC address is split into 24-bit halves.</li><li>2-The hex constant FFFE is inserted between the two halves to complete the 64-bit address. For example, 10-01-64-AB-78-96 becomes: 1001:64FF:FEAB:7896 .</li><li>3-The seventh bit of the MAC address (reading from left to right) is set to binary 1. This bit is called the universal/local (U/L) bit.</li></ul><ul><li>Modifying the seventh binary bit modifies the second hex value in the address.</li><li>For a MAC address of 10-01-64-AB-78-96, the first two hex values translate to the following binary number: 0001 0000</li><li>Setting the seventh bit to 1 yields 0001 0010, which translates into 12 hex. In this example, the MAC address of 10-01-64-AB-78-96 in modified EUI-64 format becomes: 1201:64FF:FEAB:7896 (portions in red indicate modified values). Addresses with a FC00::/7 prefix are unique local addresses. </li></ul>","section":"4.2","qnum":"09"}
    ]
}